Phong Nguyen

Senior Software Engineer

With 19 years of experience, I'm passionate about software architecture and writing maintainable code. I've focused on modern JavaScript frameworks for the past five years, but I can pick up any technology stack quickly and easily.

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam (+84) 773 008 452 phongnn@gmail.com https://phongnn.dev

Experience

Senior Software Engineer. Self-employed. Jun 2018 - Present

- Created a progressive web app (PWA) for personal productivity, using
 React, OnsenUI on frontend, Express on backend, and Firestore database.
- Created a website that provided programming courses in Vietnamese.
 Used Next.js, Ant Design on frontend, Express and Firestore on backend.
- Created programming courses: JavaScript, React, Redux, Express...

Delivery Manager / Architect at FPT Software Malaysia. Dec 2015 - May 2018

- Played a key role in establishing FPT as a preferred outsource vendor for Malaysia's largest mail and parcel delivery company. Completed three projects of good quality and within budget.
- Designed a payment switch and the integration parts of a large bill payment system for the client.

Senior Developer at Potentiate Sdn Bhd (Malaysia). Aug 2014 - Sep 2015 Potentiate was an Australian market research company where I maintained a Java desktop survey designer, troubleshot online surveys, and developed web apps for visualizing survey results.

Senior Developer at FPT Software Malaysia. Feb 2010 - May 2014 FPT is a global leader in software outsourcing with many clients in Malaysia.

- Designed and implemented ETL solutions for Malaysia's largest oil and gas company, including a data mart for retail customer loyalty with around 4 million cards and 250,000 daily transactions.
- Designed and implemented an ETL solution for a large commercial bank to generate reports on loan management for the Central Bank of Malaysia.

Programming Teacher at Aptech Vietnam. Sep 2008 - Jan 2010 Taught object-oriented programming, Java, SQL Server, XML...

Team Lead at FPT Software (Vietnam). Jun 2006 - Jul 2008 Led three different teams of six to ten members on a large project that migrated over 1,000 applications from Lotus Notes to Microsoft SharePoint for a multinational oil and gas company.

Skills

System Design

Clean architecture, design principles & patterns, domain-driven design, microservices

Languages & Runtimes

JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Cloudflare Workers

Frameworks & Libraries

React, Next.js, Remix, Express, Apollo Server

Databases

MySQL, MongoDB, Redis

Others

WebSocket, RabbitMQ, Jest, React Testing Library, Cypress, Docker

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (Information Technology)

Posts & Telecommunications Institute of Technology Hanoi (Vietnam), 1999-2003

Master of Science (Business Intelligence & Analytics) Universiti Teknologi Malaysia Kuala Lumpur, 2020-2021